# Kaitlyn Ellsweig

Little Egg Harbor, NJ 08087 | 732-956-8227 | kaitlynellsweig@gmail.com | github | portfolio | linkedin

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

I am a data scientist with a background in political science and economics. In my past experiences in management, research, and campaigns, I have honed leadership, critical thinking and communication skills. I have experience managing and analyzing datasets and communicating findings with data visualization tools and reports. My ultimate goal is to utilize these abilities along with my technical skills as part of a team that turns data into actionable insights.

#### SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Sci-kit Learn, SQL, R, PySpark
- Machine Learning: Regression, NLP, KNearest Neighbors, Naive Bayes, Random Forests, Boosting, Support Vector Machines, Recommender Systems, Clustering, Neural Networks, Dimensionality Reduction
- Software: Stata, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau

#### **PROJECTS**

# Coronavirus Pandemic Analysis Project, Project Manager

- Led a team that analyzed covid-19 pandemic outcomes at the state and county level to generate recommendations for specific policies to better prepare for a future pandemic
- Developed and analyzed a linear regression model that explained over 93% of variability in case and death counts at the county level with statistically significant features
- Built a Tableau dashboard and drafted a technical report to communicate findings and policy recommendations

## Reddit Post Analysis with NLP, Data Scientist

- Developed a machine learning model that classified Reddit posts with 99.6% accuracy
- Utilized PRAW API to scrape Reddit posts from r/ultralight and r/camping to collect over 12,000 posts
- Conducted exploratory data analysis, cleaned and combined datasets, and created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn libraries

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Friends of the Cobbossee Watershed, Volunteer Data Scientist

Remote, Nov. 2023 - Present

- Analyzed budget and inspection data for an environmental nonprofit, Friends of the Cobbossee Watershed
- Developed a machine learning model to predict the number of courtesy boat inspections at a given location and deployed this model to predict the number of inspections the nonprofit would conduct in 2024
- Created a budget function to project the increase in cost to the nonprofit if the organization covered more shifts or increased the base wage of their employees

#### General Assembly, Data Science Immersive Fellow

Remote, Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2023

• Completed 500+ hours of expert led instruction in machine learning, statistical modeling, and data analysis Completed projects utilizing OLS, classification models, APIs, Machine Learning, Neural Nets, and SQL

#### Wawa, Food and Beverage Manager

Little Egg Harbor, NJ, Jun. 2019- Sep. 2023

- Responsible for hiring, training and development of store team comprised of 60+ associates
- Analyzed sales data and implemented changes resulting in more than 10% sales increase across multiple categories
- Improved secret shopper scores by 20% through associate training and process changes

#### Center for Policy Research, Research Assistant

Syracuse, NY, Jan. 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Managed high-dimensionality, high-volume database containing confidential data on over 20M NYC students
- Compiled, cleaned and analyzed data utilizing MS Access, MS Excel, and Stata to assist with projects evaluating the performance of the Universal Free Lunch program in NYC public schools

## **Congressional Campaign, Finance Intern**

Syracuse, NY, May. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Compiled and analyzed data from internal databases and public records to develop targeted outreach strategies
- Contributed to fundraising effort totaling over \$2.7 million

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly, Data Science Immersive

Syracuse University, B.A. Political Science | B.A. Economics

Syracuse, NY, Degree: May 2024

Certificate: Dec. 2023